# **Bruno Coutinho**



#### Who I am

Since my very first introduction to the advertising environment as an intern some years ago, I have felt a strong drive to become an expert in this field. My history working in the programmatic environment includes acquiring skills in Ad Serving, Digital Strategies, Advertising, Marketing Strategies, and Digital Marketing. I've also become a specialist in troubleshooting, Programmatic Advertising, and Real-Time Bidding. My years of experience in this field total up to 12 (7+ years of experience in the programmatic universe and 9+ years of ad serving and digital marketing analysis: publishers, branding, advertising solutions).



#### **SKILLS**

- Publishers Inventory Monetization
- Programmatic Buying Trading
- Demand and Supply needs
- Data Providers
- Ad Formats: Video, Audio, Display
   & Native
- Technical Advice and deep troubleshooting

#### SPECIFIC SKILLS

- Rest API
- MySQL
- HTML 5
- Office
- Sales Force
- Jira
- Looker Studio

#### INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

- Quick thinking and proactive creativity
- Data oriented
- Problem Solver
- Willing to help

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Client Services Manager LATAM (An Affle Company) 10/2022 – Actually



Working in the Customer Success team as part of Client Facing helping all clients with proposals, optimizations, and presenting QBRs every quarter. Also we support as comercial and sales teams in any strategic events (e.g. DigiTalks, MMA Impact, etc.) to get more clients, and also another job is helping our supply global team in the region, when needed with some SSPs, DMPs and all the partners in any issues, tasks or integrations. And in other hand, working like a trader directly to IO campaigns managing it like third-party service to the agencies.

Senior Analyst – Product Support Xandr (A Microsoft Company) Dec 2019 – Aug 2022





Participating in DMP (Data Management Platform) SMEship to get more specialized on different products to support all partners and customers. Completed the Front-End training plan (challenge) for Latam Services of web development and additionally, building a "Template Gallery" page to put into practice my acquired skills. Helped with the LATAM commercial team in ECD (Exchange Curated Deal) in our internal communication tool (deep investigations as SME about ECD). Worked on the buddy program with our new Trading and SC teams employees. And presented bi-weekly case reviews in our PS LATAM Sync to all Latam services team.

## **Bruno Coutinho**



#### **EDUCATION**

- Technologist in Systems
   Analysis FMU FIAM/FAAM
   Morumbi
- CC50: Introduction of Computer Science – Harvard Course in Brazil
- Post Degree in Big Data –
   Anhembi Morumbi University

#### **BUSINESS TRAVEL**

- New York, USA 2017 -AppNexus Team Building
- Mexico City, Mexico 2020 -Xandr LATAM Off-Site

#### **LANGUAGES**

- Portuguese Native
- Spanish Intermediate
- English Advanced

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Associate Product Support Specialist Xandr (AT&T Group) Oct 2018 – Nov 2019



Performing Product Support duties, participating in Creative SMEship to get more specialized on that product from our platform helping Support L2 and engineering to clear questions related to this (internal and external), completed the CAP program during H2 and Starting to work with Managers and HRs doing phone screens to talk to candidates into the open roles for the region.

## Associate Product Support Specialist AppNexus Jul 2015 – Nov 2019



Programmatic Environment: Buy-side, Sell-side, Deals, Creatives, Advertising and others. Supporting the LATAM/EMEA customers working with our programmatic platform (Console). Worked with API RESTful, some MySQL queries, basic HTML 5, to help the customers with data, check integrations, some adjusting in hosted creatives files, etc.

## Support Analyst / Front-End Support Realmedia Latin America Jan 2013 – Jun 2015



Support to the customers about our functionalities and usability regarding our system as implementation, best practices on how to use, generating reports, monitoring the delivery via UI, helping AdOps team with general topics and assistance in our delivery and checking our tags from OAS (adserver) into the customer websites.